Register of the Sidney Hook papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1917-1990 (Boxes 31-101)
  - "The Political Motivation of Fichte's Thought," Holograph and typescript (Folder 23)
  - "The Political Motivation of Marx's Thought," Typescript, outlines, clipping, notes, and bibliography (Folder 24)
  - "The Political Motivation of Schelling's Thought," Holograph and typescript (Folder 25)
  - "Political Necrophobia," n.d. Review of Margaret Halsey, The Pseudo-Ethic. Typescript (Folder 26)
  - "Possibility in History," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 27)
  - "Professionalization vs. Politicization of the Universities," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 28)
  - "Professor Sidney Hook Attacks Stalinazism," People's Forum, Printed copy, n.d. (Folder 29)
  - "Propositions," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 30)
  - "The Purpose and Nature of General Education," Typescript (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - "Reflections on Europe," Typescript and clipping (Folder 2)
  - "Reflections on Freedom," Typescripts, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "Reflections on Important Themes," Holograph outline and a letter from Sidney Ratner relating to Sir John Hackett (Folder 4)
  - "The Rehabilitation of Hegel," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - "The Relation of Legal Systems to Social Change," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - "Religion and the Law," Holograph (Folder 7)
  - "Religion and Society," n.d Typescript (Folder 8)
  - "Religion and Society: A Rejoinder," Typescript (Folder 9)
  - "Report on Meyer: Unity of Theory and Practice in Marxist Dialectic," Typescript (Folder 10)
  - Review of Henry D. Aiken, Predicament of the University, Holograph, typescript, and a copy of an essay by Aiken (Folder 11)
  - Review of C. E. Ayres, Toward a Reasonable Society: The Values of Industrial Civilization, Holograph (Folder 12)
  - Review of George Benson and Thomas Engeman, Amoral America, Typescript (Folder 13)
  - Review of James Bryant Conant, Education in a Divided World, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - Review of Jerome Davis, Capitalism and Its Culture, Typescript (Folder 15)
  - Review of Lewis Feuer, Einstein and the Generations of Science, Typescript (Folder 16)
  - Review of William James, Pragmatism, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 17)
  - Review of John Stuart Mill, On Liberty, Holograph outline, n.d. (Folder 18)
  - Review of Hans Reichenbach, Experience and Prediction: An Analysis of the Foundations and the Structure of Knowledge, Notes and typescript (Folder 19)
  - Review of Harold Rugg, The Great Technology, Social Chaos and the Public Mind, Typescript (Folder 20)
  - Review of Leon Samson, The American Mind: A Study in Socio- Analysis, Typescript (Folder 21)
  - Review of Jean-Paul Sartre, The Psychology of the Imagination, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 22)
  - Review of Paul Arthur Schilpp, ed., The Philosophy of G. E. Moore, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 23)
  - "The Revival of Conservatism," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 24)
  - "The Revival of Racialism Redivivus," n.d. Holograph, notes, and clippings, 1964-1968 (Folder 25)
  - "Richard Krygier: An Appreciation," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 26)
  - "Russia in Retrospect," n.d. Review of Victor Chernov, The Great Russian Revolution. Typescript (Folder 27)
  - "The Russian Revolution and American Intellectuals," Holograph (Folder 28)
  - "Science and Freedom," Introduction to speech by Robert Sherwood. Holograph and typescript (Folder 29)
  - "Signposts," Projected book to be co-authored with others; never completed. Typescript outlines, n.d. (Folder 30)
  - "Six Modern Concepts of Rationality," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 31)
  - "Some Reflections on 'The Magic of Marxism' and 'The Next Stage of History,'" Typescript (Folder 32)
  - Speech, Relates to dissent and civil disorder. Holograph (incomplete) (Folder 33)
  - Speech, American Philosophical Association symposium on "The Future of Liberalism," New York. Clipping, n.d. (Folder 34)
  - Speech, Brandeis University, Notes and typescript (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Speech, Columbia University, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Speech, Congress for Cultural Freedom meeting, Typewritten transcript, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Speech, Individual Liberty and the American Tradition Conference, Barnard College, Mimeograph (Folder 4)
  - Speech, New School for Social Research, Relates to the Warsaw uprising. Typescript, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Speech, University Centers for Rational Alternatives conference, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Speech for a discussion entitled "The Philosophical Man", Typescript, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - Speech in honor of Thomas Pollock, Holograph and typescript (Folder 8)
  - Speech on democracy, Typescript (Folder 9)
  - Speech on student protest, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 10)
  - Speech on the Tamiment Institute, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - "Spengler's Philosophy of History," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - "The Strategy of Freedom," Holograph, notes, and printed background material relating to Russia and defense (Folder 13)
  - "The Strategy of Political Warfare," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - "The Supreme Court Runs Amok," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 15)
  - "A Tale of Two Countries," Holograph (incomplete), n.d. (Folder 16)
  - "Theses on Feuerbach and Communism as the Ethics of Love," and "Arnold Ruge and Karl Marx," in Images of Human Existence: The Marxist Image of Human Existence, Printed table of contents (Folder 17)
  - "Tradition, Authority and Freedom," Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "The Tragic View of History," n.d. Review of Morris R. Cohen, The Meaning of Human History. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - "A Tribute to Max Nomad," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 20)
  - Undergraduate English essays, City College of New York, Holograph and typescript (Folder 21)
  - Untitled autobiographical fragments, Holographs, n.d. (Folder 22)
  - Untitled fragment on anarchism and violence, Holograph (Folder 23)
  - Untitled fragment on communism, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 24)
  - Untitled fragment on God, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 25)
  - Untitled fragment on human rights, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 26)
  - Untitled fragment on human values and economic policy, n.d. Holograph with holograph invitation to Kenneth Arrow to participate in seminar scheduled for, May 1966 (Folder 27)
  - Untitled fragment on Harold Laski, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 28)
  - Untitled fragment on philosophy, Holograph outline of chapters for a book (?), n.d. (Folder 29)
  - Untitled fragment on Ezra Pound, Holograph (Folder 30)
  - Untitled fragment on Russia, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 31)
  - Untitled fragment on Frederick L. Schuman, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 32)
  - Untitled fragment on socialism, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 33)
  - Untitled fragment on Stansfield Turner and the CIA, Typescript and notes (Folder 34)
  - Untitled fragment on universities, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 35)
  - Untitled fragment on women on university faculties, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 36)
  - Untitled fragments on civil liberties, Holographs, n.d. (Folder 37)
  - Untitled fragments on Morris Cohen, Holographs and typescript (Folder 38)
  - Untitled fragments on communism in education, Holographs, n.d. (Folder 39)
  - Untitled fragments on the Congress for Cultural Freedom, Holographs, n.d. (Folder 40)
  - Untitled fragments on John Dewey, Holographs and typescript (Folder 41)
  - Untitled fragments on discrimination, Holograph (Folder 42)
  - Untitled fragments on education, Holographs and printed copy (Folder 43)
  - Untitled fragments on ethics, Holographs, n.d. (Folder 44)
  - Untitled fragments on international relations, Holograph, typescripts, and printed copy (Folder 45)
  - Untitled fragments on Judaism, Holographs, n.d. (Folder 46)
  - Untitled fragments on Jean-Paul Sartre and Karl Marx, Holographs (Folder 47)
  - Untitled writing on civil rights, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 48)
  - Untitled writing on education, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 49)
  - Untitled writing on foreign relations, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 50)
  - Untitled writing on G. W. F. Hegel, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 51)
  - Untitled writing on Corliss Lamont, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 52)
  - Untitled writing on liberalism, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 53)
  - Untitled writing on Shirley MacLaine and Ring Lardner, Jr., Holograph (Folder 54)
  - Untitled writing on Karl Marx, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 55)
  - Untitled writing on nuclear weapons, Holograph, n.d.. (Folder 56)
  - Untitled writing on official secrets, Holograph, n.d. (Folder 57)
  - Untitled writing on perception, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 58)
  - Untitled writing on Philip Rahv, Walter Phillips, and Edmund Wilson, Holograph (Folder 59)
  - Untitled writing on reason, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 60)
  - Untitled writing on Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, Typescript (Folder 61)
  - Untitled writing on Russia, Typescript and holograph outline (Folder 62)
  - Untitled writing on science and the scientific method, Typescript (Folder 63)
  - Untitled writing on Stanford University, Typescript intended for insertion as a footnote (Folder 64)
  - Untitled writings on communism, Holographs, and typescript (Folder 65)
  - "The Uses of Leisure: Enjoying Life or Killing Time?" Typescript, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - "The Uses of Philosophy," Typescript, notes, and clipping, 1966 (Folder 2)
  - "Values in Contemporary Society," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "The Ways of Things," n.d. Review of William P. Montague, The Ways of Things. Typescript (Folder 4)
  - "What Are the University Centers for Rational Alternatives?" Measure, Printed copy, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - "What Has Modern Philosophy to Say?" Typescript, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - "What Is Academic Freedom?" Typescript, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - "What Is an Educated Person?" Typescript and letter, 1958 (Folder 8)
  - "What Is Class Consciousness?" Typescript, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - "What Is Security?" Outlines, notes, holograph, typescript, and an annotated copy of Hook's article, "Security and Freedom" (Folder 10)
  - "What Means this Freedom?" Typescripts, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - "Whither Socialism?" Typescript and galleys (Folder 12)
  - "Why Do I Read the American Spectator?" Typescript, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - "The World's Foremost Statesman," Relates to Woodrow Wilson. Typescripts, n.d. (Folder 14)
  - "The Young Hegelians," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 15)
  - "The Best Man I Know," Holograph, Feb. 7, 1917. (Folder 16)
  - "Love of Country," Holograph, Feb. 7, 1917. (Folder 17)
  - Flyer relating to student elections, Printed copy, ca. 1918. (Folder 18)
  - "The Pragmatic Conception of Truth and Error," Typescript, 1920. (Folder 19)
  - "An Interpretation of My Self," Typescript, Jan. 10, 1921. (Folder 20)
  - "Telluric Determinants of Culture," Undergraduate essay, City College of New York. Holograph, 1922? (Folder 21)
  - "The Philosophy of Non-Resistance," Open Court, Printed copy, Jan. 1922. (Folder 22)
  - "An Outline of Boas' Mind of Primitive Man," Undergraduate notes, City College of New York. Holograph, Sept. 1922. (Folder 23)
  - "A Philosophical Dialogue," Open Court, Printed copy, Oct. 1922. (Folder 24)
  - "Metaphysical Analysis," Typescript, Oct. 20, 1925. (Folder 25)
  - "Some Political Motives in Hegel's Thought," Holograph, typescript, and correspondence with Vladimir G. Simkhovitch, 1926 (Folder 26)
  - Review of Rebecca Cooper, The Logical Influence of Hegel on Marx, Journal of Philosophy, Printed copy, Feb. 18, 1926. (Folder 27)
  - "The Metaphysics of Leading Principles," Journal of Philosophy, Printed copy, April 1926. (Folder 28)
  - "Methodological Considerations in Primitive Art," Open Court, Printed copy, June 1926. (Folder 29)
  - Notes on lectures by John Dewey on political theory, Columbia University, Typescript, Sept. 29, 1926-Jan. 10, 1927. (Folder 30)
  - The Metaphysics of Pragmatism, 1927. Letters, 1927-1935 (Folder 31)
  - "The Ethics of Suicide," International Journal of Ethics, Printed copy and letters, 1926-1927., Jan. 1927. (Folder 32)
  - "Freedom," Open Court, Printed copy, Feb. 1927. (Folder 33)
  - "Categorical Analysis and Pragmatic-Realism," Journal of Philosophy, Printed copy, March 31, 1927. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - "The Metaphysics of the Instrument," Monist, Printed copies, July-Oct. 1927. (Folder 2)
  - "The Irrationality of the Irrational," Journal of Philosophy, Letter, 1927, Aug. 4, 1927. (Folder 3)
  - "Teaching as a Calling," Progress, Printed copy, Nov. 1927. (Folder 4)
  - "Marx and Freud: Oil and Water," Open Court, Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Max Eastman and another, 1927-1975, Jan. 1928. (Folder 5)
  - "The Philosophy of Dialectical Materialism," Journal of Philosophy, Printed copies, March 1-15, 1928. (Folder 6)
  - "Marxism, Metaphysics, and Modern Science," Modern Quarterly, May-Aug. 1928. Review of Max Eastman, Marx, Lenin, and the Science of Revolution. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "German Philosophy and Politics from " ca. 1928-1929. Progress report to the Guggenheim Foundation. Typescript, 1835 to 1842 (Folder 8)
  - "Russia from the Side-lines," Typescript (incomplete), 1929? (Folder 9)
  - "A Pragmatic Critique of the Historico-Genetic Method," in Essays in Honor of John Dewey, Typescript and printed copy, 1929. (Folder 10)
  - "What Is Dialectic?" Journal of Philosophy, Printed copy, Feb. 14-28, 1929. (Folder 11)
  - "Hegel's Staatsidee," Journal of Philosophy, Sept. 12, 1929. Review of Julius Lowenstein, Hegels Staatsidee. Letter, 1937 (Folder 12)
  - "A Critique of Ethical Realism," International Journal of Ethics, Printed copy and letters, 1929-1930, Jan. 1930. (Folder 13)
  - "A Personal Impression of Contemporary German Philosophy," Journal of Philosophy, Printed copy and correspondence with Gordon Allport, Hans Reichenbach, Philip Wheelwright, and others, 1930, March 13, 1930. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - "Revolt against Dualism," New Republic, June 1930. Review of Arthur Lovejoy, Revolt against Dualism. Letter (Folder 2)
  - "Husserl's Phenomenological Idealism," Journal of Philosophy, July 3, 1930. Review of Edmund Husserl, Formale und Transzendentale Logik. Letter (Folder 3)
  - "Contemporary American Philosophy," New Republic, July 16, 1930. Review of George P. Adams and William Pepperell Montague, ed., Contemporary American Philosophy: Personal Statements. Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "The Philosophy of Morris R. Cohen," New Republic, Printed copy and letters by Bruce Bliven and others, 1930, July 23, 1930. (Folder 5)
  - "The American Road to Culture," Current History, Oct. 1930. Review of George S. Counts, The American Road to Culture. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "Capitalism and Protestantism," Nation, Oct. 29, 1930. Review of Max Weber, The Protestant Ethic and the Spirit of Capitalism. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "The Meaning of Marxism," Modern Quarterly, Contribution to a symposium. Printed copy, Dec. 1930. (Folder 8)
  - "The Non-Sense of the Whole," Modern Quarterly, Review, and letters by S. Klyce and George B. Vetter, 1931, Dec. 1930. (Folder 9)
  - "Psychology," Holograph and notes, 1931. (Folder 10)
  - "The Psychology of Socialism," Current History, Jan. 1931. Review of Henri de Man, The Psychology of Socialism. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 11)
  - "John Dewey and His Critics," New Republic, Typescript, June 3, 1931. (Folder 12)
  - "Towards the Understanding of Karl Marx," Symposium, Printed copy, clipping, and letters by Malcolm Cowley, Felix Frankfurter, H. M. Kallen, Arthur G. McDowell, Meyer Schapiro and others, 1931-1932., July 1931. (Folder 13)
  - "Marx and Darwinism," New Republic, Letter by Charles A. Beard, 1931, July 29, 1931. (Folder 14)
  - "Experimental Logic," Mind, Printed copy, and letters by G. E. Moore, Harry Overstreet, Roscoe Pound, Meyer Schapiro, Harold R. Smart, and others, 1931-1932, Oct. 1931. (Folder 15)
  - "The Metaphysics of Experience," New Republic, Nov. 4, 1931. Review of John Dewey, Philosophy and Civilization. Typescript and printed copy (incomplete) (Folder 16)
  - "A Call to Defend Academic Freedom and Students' Rights," (co-authored with others). Printed copy, 1932 (Folder 17)
  - "Hegel's Intent," Philosophical Review, Jan. 1932. Review of Theodor L. Haering, Hegel: Sein Wollen und Sein Werk: Eine Chronologische Entwicklungsgeschichte der Gedanken und der Sprache Hegels, Vol. I. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - "Reason and Nature: The Metaphysics of Scientific Method," Journal of Philosophy, Jan. 7, 1932. Review of Morris R. Cohen, Reason and Nature. Holographs, typescript, printed copy, draft letter to contributors with list, and letters by Cohen, Paul Weiss and others (Folder 19)
  - "Pictures of the Past," Saturday Review, April 30, 1932. Review of M. N. Pokrovsky, History of Russia, Vol. I. Typescript (Folder 20)
  - "Charles Peirce: Collected Papers," Current History, May 1932. Review of Collected Papers of Charles Peirce. Typescript and letter, 1931 (Folder 21)
  - "The Contemporary Significance of Hegel's Philosophy," Philosophical Review, Printed copy, and letters by Theodore B. Brameld and others, 1932, May 1932. (Folder 22)
  - "Hegel and Marx in Continuity," Modern Quarterly, Letter by Meyer Schapiro, 1932, Summer 1932. (Folder 23)
  - "Half-Baked Communism," Nation, June 8, 1932. Review of Robert Briffault, Breakdown: The Collapse of Traditional Civilization. Printed copy, printed copies of comments by Briffault and others, and letter by Brand Blanshard (Folder 24)
  - "Hegel's Phenomenology of Mind," Journal of Philosophy, June 23, 1932. Review of G. W. F. Hegel, Phenomenology of Mind. Printed copy (Folder 25)
  - "Myth, Fact, and Poetry of Soviet Russia," Nation, Sept. 14, 1932. Review of Waldemar Gurian, Bolshevism: Theory and Practice, Joseph Freeman, The Soviet Worker, Waldo Frank, Dawn in Russia, and George S. Counts, Luigi Villari, Malcolm C. Rorty and Newton D. Baker, Bolshevism, Fascism, and Capitalism. Printed copy (Folder 26)
  - Culture and the Crisis: An Open Letter to the Writers, Artists, Teachers, Physicians, Engineers, Scientists and Other Professional Workers of America, (co-authored with other members of the League of Professional Groups for Foster and Ford). Pamphlet. Printed copy and letter by Frederick L. Schuman, 1960, Oct. 1932 (Folder 27)
  - "The Marxist Interpretation of History," Printed program announcement, Nov. 27, 1932. (Folder 28)
  - "Materialism," Encyclopaedia of the Social Sciences, Holograph, typescript and correspondence, 1932, 1933. (Folder 29)
  - Open letter to President Franklin D. Roosevelt, (co-authored with 34 others). Relates to Soviet-American relations. Printed copy, 1933 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Speech, Relates to Karl Marx. Holograph, 1933. (Folder 2)
  - Towards the Understanding of Karl Marx, 1933
    - General. Notes by Hook, promotional leaflet, and reviews, 1933-1934 (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with John Anderson, Newton Arvin, Louis D. Brandeis, Morris R. Cohen, George S. Counts, R. Palme Dutt, Abe Edel, Abram L. Harris, Will Herberg, D. Liberson, Alfred Rosmer, Morris U. Schappes, Roy Wood Sellars, Bernhard J. Stern, Edmund Wilson and others, 1932-1984 (Folder 4)
  - Untitled writing, Reply to V. J. Jerome's article "Unmasking an American Revisionist of Marxism." Holograph, 1933. (Folder 5)
  - Interview, Typewritten transcript and printed copy, March 11, 1933. (Folder 6)
  - "Marxism: Dogma or Method?" Nation, Typescript, printed copy, clipping, and letters by Horace L. Friess and another, 1933, March 15, 1933. (Folder 7)
  - "The Marxian Dialectic," New Republic, Printed letter to the editor by W. C. Mallalieu relating to Hook's article, March 22, 1933. (Folder 8)
  - "Against the Fascist Terror in Germany," New Masses, Contribution to symposium. Printed copy, April 1933. (Folder 9)
  - "Russia in Solution," Saturday Review, April 8, 1933. Review of Leon Trotsky, The History of the Russian Revolution, Vols. II and III. Printed copy and letter, 1932 (Folder 10)
  - "Why the German Student Is Fascist," Student Outlook, Printed copy, May 1933. (Folder 11)
  - "Philosophy and Social Action," Speech, New York University. Notes and press release, May 18, 1933. (Folder 12)
  - "Education and Politics," New Republic, May 24, 1933. Review of John L. Childs and John Dewey, ed., The Educational Frontier. Typescript (Folder 13)
  - "Science and the Crisis," Nation, June 21, 1933. Review of H. L. Levy, The Universe of Science, and Mary Adams, ed., Science and the Changing World. Printed copy (Folder 14)
  - "Revolutionist's Symposium," Nation, June 28, 1933. Review of Samuel D. Schmalhausen, ed., Recovery through Revolution. Printed copy (Folder 15)
  - "Correspondence: Trotzky and Sidney Hook," Nation, Letter to the editor in reply to comments by Leon Trotsky on Hook's article "Marxism: Dogma or Method?" Typescript, printed copy, and typescript and printed copies of the letter by Trotskii, 1933, July 5, 1933. (Folder 16)
  - "De Libris: Disputatio," City College Alumnus, Sept. 1933. Letter to the editor relating to a review by David P. Berenberg of Hook's book Towards the Understanding of Karl Marx. Printed copy, and printed copy of Berenberg's review (Folder 17)
  - "Theories of Social Determinism," Scientia, Printed copy, Dec. 1933. (Folder 18)
  - The Meaning of Marx: A Symposium, 1934 (co-author with Bertrand Russell, John Dewey, Morris R. Cohen and Sherwood Eddy). Pamphlet. Printed copy, correspondence, and printed articles by L. Rudas, "The Meaning of Sidney Hook,", 1935-1951 (Folder 19)
  - "Is Marxism Compatible with Christianity?" Christian Register, Printed copy and letter, 1934, Feb. 15, 1934. (Folder 20)
  - "The Nature of Discourse," Saturday Review, March 10, 1934. Review of Alfred Korzybksi, Science and Sanity: An Introduction to Non-Aristotelian Systems and General Semantics. Typescript, printed copy, and letter by Korzybski, 1934-1941 (Folder 21)
  - "Communism without Dogmas," Modern Monthly, Letters by E. F. Carritt, V. J. McGill and Allen Stiller, 1934, April 1934. (Folder 22)
  - "What is Materialism?" Journal of Philosophy, Printed copy, April 26, 1934. (Folder 23)
  - "The Role of the Educator," Student Outlook, Printed copy, May 1934. (Folder 24)
  - "Marxism and Democracy: Some Notes on the Draft Program of the A. W. P.," Labor Action, Printed copy, May 1, 1934. (Folder 25)
  - "Sidney Hook Replies," Commonwealth College Fortnightly, June 15, 1934. Letter to the editor in reply to a review by William Cunningham of Hook's book Towards the Understanding of Karl Marx. Printed copy. Includes printed copies of the review by Cunningham and of comments by Paul Evans on Hook's reply (Folder 26)
  - "The Fallacy of the Theory of Social Fascism," Modern Monthly, Printed copy, and letter by Meyer Schapiro, 1934, July 1934. (Folder 27)
  - Letter to the editor, New Republic, (date written). Relates to Lincoln Steffens. Typescript, Aug. 4, 1934 (Folder 28)
  - "The Challenge of the Social Order to the Curriculum of the Liberal Arts College," Speech, National Council on Religion in Higher Education, Colgate- Rochester Divinity School, Rochester, N.Y. Printed copy, Sept. 1934. (Folder 29)
  - "An Open Letter to Lincoln Steffens," Modern Monthly, Printed copy, Sept. 1934. (Folder 30)
  - "On Workers' Democracy," Modern Monthly, Printed copy, printed copies of responses by Will Herberg and M. Rieve, and letters by Paul Mattick, Paul Porter, Meyer Schapiro and Allen Stiller, 1934-1935, Oct. 1934. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - "The Importance of a Point of View," Social Frontier, Two-part article. Printed copy, Oct.-Nov. 1934. (Folder 2)
  - "The Democratic and Dictatorial Aspects of Communism," International Conciliation, Printed copy and letters, 1934-1935, Dec. 1934. (Folder 3)
  - "Karl Marx and Moses Hess," New International, Clipping, and correspondence with Jack Nusan Porter, 1981, Dec. 1934. (Folder 4)